In this clip I want to talk to you about freestyle motocross.
Freestyle motocross really kind of putting itself on the map.
You know it used to be just kind of be a lot of free riding out in the hills, maybe out in California, Beaumont, Artille Wells, a lot of places like that.
Guys just hitting dirt jumps.
Now these days it's come into the stadiums, into the X-Games, the Gravity Games, the Mountain Dew Tour.
It's the entire series.
So as well as the motocross and the supercross series they also have freestyle actual series.
You can catch them on TV all the time.
I'd say Nate Adams, Travis Pastrana and Kenny Bartram, these guys, you know, they've all just been instrumental in the motocross scene.
Back in 1999 when Carey Hart flew his first backflip in New York at the Gravity Games, that was just a huge moment for motocross.
Now you've got guys like Travis Pastrana doing double backflips and variations into their flips and a lot of really cool stuff coming from motocross.
There's kind of a different way to set up your bike for freestyling.
This bike, or my bike, is primarily motocross, but a lot of guys they cut down their seats.
You know make their seat foams really thin because they're not, you know they're not needing to do the moto.
They're not needing that cush in that seat to go faster on those corners and they've got a lot of big, say hand holds back here and their suspension might tend to be really stiff because you know they're on average jumping about 100 foot plus jumps.
So you're really going to want to, you know, absorb those landings and their bikes are completely set up for that.
Maybe a little taller bars.
No cross pads because they're doing a lot of in and out or putting their feet up here all the time.
You don't want to be getting hung up on anything like that.
And a lot of events are really getting pretty big.
So that's also a cool thing is a lot of media coverage from this sport.
So take a look online, you know, there's a lot of freestyle events, national and more local that are probably going to be near you.
Come check it out and that stuff.
I can't personally do a lot of the tricks that they can do on there but it's real exciting to see in person.